Earth.
土强
本作品采用知识共享CC BY-NC-SA共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可
本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流，请勿用作商业用途！
Fire.
火烈
Air.
气和
Water.
水善
Only the Avatar can master all four elements
只有神通能掌握所有四种元素
and bring balance to the world.
并为世界带来平衡
降世神通：科拉传奇
Bolin's a hero.
波林成了英雄
The mover star stopped Varrick's kidnapping attempt on president Raiko,
这位电影明星阻止了瓦里克绑架雷鼓总统
proving his brother's innocence.
证明了他哥哥是无罪的
Mako and Korra were reunited, but Korra has no memory of their breakup.
信和科拉重聚，但科拉忘记了分手的事
Meanwhile, Jinora's spirit is still trapped in the spirit world,
同时，吉诺拉的魂魄仍然被困在灵界
and Tonraq and his southern forces have been defeated.
托纳克和他的南方部队已经被打败了
Now it's up to team Avatar to stop Unalaq before harmonic convergence.
现在只有神通小队能在谐波汇聚之前阻止吴纳克
第二册：神灵篇
第十二集：谐波汇聚
What's up with the coat?
这件外套是怎么回事？
And where did you get that pie?
还有，你从哪儿搞到的馅饼？
It's a Varrick ship. You never know what you're gonna find.
这是瓦里克的船，你永远不知道你会发现什么
There's a whole level filled with funhouse mirrors.
这里有一整层都摆满了哈哈镜的船舱
Of course, there's also the cat-gator deck.
还有一层甲板全都是猫鳄
I miss that guy.
我想念那个家伙了
He really knew how to make a long trip interesting.
他真的知道怎么让漫漫旅途变得充满乐趣
So have you told Korra yet about how
那么，你告诉科拉了吗？
you guys broke up
关于你们分手
and then you kind of started dating Asami while she was off getting attacked by dark spirits?
然后在她被暗灵攻击时你又跟麻美约会什么的
You wanna keep it down?
你能小点声吗
I'm waiting for the right moment.
我在等合适的时机
Oh, Mako.
哦，信
You know, a wise man once told me that delivering bad news to a girlfriend
有个聪明人曾经说过，告诉女朋友坏消息
was like ripping off a blood-sucking leech. You just have to do it fast and get it over with.
就像撕掉一个吸血水蛭，你只需要动作快点并了结它
I hate it when you listen to me.
我真讨厌你听我话的时候
Fine.
好吧
Unalaq will be waiting for you.
吴纳克知道你会来的
You'll need all of your Avatar power to stop him.
你必须用上全部神通之力去阻止他
I'm going to close the spirit portals,
我会关闭灵界通道
lock Vaatu in for another 10,000 years,
把瓦图再关上个一万年
and make Unalaq wish he'd never been born!
然后让吴纳克后悔自己出生于世
Nice Battleship！！
Thanks, Mako.
谢谢你，信
Did you want something?
你想说什么吗
Uh, no, no, nothing.
不不，没什么
As soon as we reach the Southern water tribe,
等我们一到达南极水族部落
we'll blast through the blockade at the main port.
我们首先要冲破主要港口的封锁线
Then we can rendezvous with Tonraq and his troops,
然后我们就可以和托纳克以及他的部队集结
crash through the defenses around the portal, and enter the spirit world.
击垮守卫通道的防御力量，之后进入灵界
Whoa, since when does my little brother want to crash or blast through anything?
哇，什么时候开始我的弟弟想要击垮破坏东西了？
I'll do whatever it takes to save my daughter.
我会不惜一切来拯救我女儿
We all want to save Jinora,
我们都想去救吉诺拉
but I think your plan might be a tad overaggressive,
但我觉得你的计划可能有一点太过于激进了
seeing as there are only seven of us and one ship.
要知道我们只有七个人和一艘船
Really?
怎么了？
And what do you suggest?
那么你有什么建议？
An attack like this calls for strategy.
像这样的进攻要讲究策略
I remember when I was surrounded by pirates in the hurricane straits.
我记得有次我在一个风暴海峡被海盗们团团围住
We managed to capture them all
我们最后仅凭一根羽毛
with just a feather, two eggs, and a barrel of molasses.
两个鸡蛋和一桶糖浆就将他们尽数捕获
I don't want to hear any of your crazy stories now.
在我不想再听到你的任何鬼扯了
This is serious.
这是很严肃的事情
Are we almost there?
我们快到了吗？
Almost.
就快了
But
但是
I just picked up a distress signal from the Southern troops.
我刚刚从南方部队收到一个不好的消息
There's a problem.
有问题
Mom!
母亲
I'm so happy you're here.
在这里见到你真高兴
Where's dad?
父亲在哪儿？
Unalaq wiped out the entire Southern resistance
吴纳克荡平了南水部队的所有抵抗
and captured your father.
并且抓到了你父亲
I'll get him back.
我会把他救回来
Where is my mother?
我母亲在哪儿
She's in the healing hut.
她在治疗房里
So many injured.
伤员太多了
What happened?
发生什么事了
Her soul is trapped in the spirit world.
她的灵魂被困在灵界了
Oh, my goodness.
哦，我的天啊
How long has she been away?
她已经去了多久了
Almost a week.
将近一周
I've tried to keep her energy flowing,
我一直试着让她的能量保持流动
but I can feel her slipping away.
但我能感觉到她在不断远离我
You're the only one who can help her now, mom.
母亲，现在只有你能救她了
How much longer can she survive like this?
她这样还能再存活多久
I don't know.
我不知道
But she's very strong to have lasted this long.
但她能坚持这么久已经很厉害了
I talked to the rebels.
我和反抗者谈过了
They said Unalaq's got the Southern portal surrounded.
他们说吴纳克把南极通道团团围住了
Harmonic convergence is only a few hours away.
离谐波汇聚只有几个小时了
Then we have to break through the enemy lines ourselves and get to the portal now.
那么现在我们只能自己去打破敌人的防线，然后进入通道了
There's no use in talking anymore.
没有必要再继续讨论了
We know what our mission is.
我们已经明白任务是什么
A suicide mission.
自杀式行动吗？
You know, I was in a similar situation once.
要知道，我曾经遇到过类似的情形
My platoon had crawled through the desert with no water for a week,
我的排要在没有水的情况下在一周内爬过沙漠
but when we finally located the only oasis for 100 Miles,
但当我们终于找到一百里内唯一的绿洲时
it was surrounded by angry sandbenders.
它却被愤怒的沙宗包围着
I realized our only chance to get to the water
我意识到我们唯一靠近水源的机会
was to drop in from above.
是从上空降落
So I fashioned together a catapult,
所以我制作了一个弹射器
and with the help of a few well-trained hog-monkeys...
在几只训练有素的猪猴的帮助下
enough of your ridiculous lies.
不要再说你那荒谬的胡话了
Can't you see that the fate of the world
你没发现整个世界的命运和吉诺拉的性命
and Jinora's life depends on what we do here today?
都取决于我们今天所做之事了吗？
Hold on. Maybe Bumi's right.
等等，也许布米说的对
We don't have a catapult and hog-monkeys,
我们没有弹射器和猪猴
but we have a flying bison, and there's a plane on Varrick's ship.
但是我们有一只飞天野牛，而且瓦里克的船上有一架飞机
Maybe we can attack from above.
没准我们就能从上空进攻
What are you thinking?
你的想法是
Mako, Bolin, and I can use the plane to create a distraction and scatter some of the defenses.
信，波林和我用飞机来分散注意力，打散一些防御力量
You, Tenzin, Bumi, and Kya can fly into the spirit portal on Oogi when you see an opening.
你，丹增，布米和凯娅乘坐无忌找开口进入灵界通道
Let's get moving.
我们行动吧
What are we still doing here, father?
我们还留在这里做什么，父亲
The invasion was completely successful,
入侵行动完全成功
and the Southern tribe is under our control.
南水部落在我们掌控之下
The spirit portals are open.
灵界通道已经打开
You've restored balance.
你已经恢复了平衡
Now we would like to go home.
现在我们想要回家了
You don't understand.
你们不懂
Everything I've achieved so far will pale in comparison with what I'm about to accomplish.
我迄今完成的每件事，与我将要完成之事相比都会黯然失色
What else is there? The water tribe is united.
还要做什么？水族部落已经合并了
After today, there will be no more water tribe,
从今往后，这里将再没有水族部落
no more nations of any kind.
没有种族和国家
The world is about to be transformed into something magnificent and new,
世界将会转变成无比壮观又崭新的存在
and I will lead this glorious revolution.
而我将会领导这场华丽的革命
Now go outside and get the troops ready to defend the spirit portal.
现在出去让部队做好守卫灵界通道的准备
From whom?
防御谁？
We've already beaten everyone.
我们已经打败了所有人
The Avatar will be here soon.
神通很快就要到了
She has no choice.
她没别的选择
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗
I'm an earthbender strapped to the wing of a plane hundreds of feet in the air,
我是一个被固定在上百尺高空的机翼上的御土师
so no.
所以没有
Don't worry. There's no way they'll be expecting this.
别担心，他们万万不会预料到这招的
I think they were expecting it.
我想他们预料到了
Asami!
麻美
Get ready.
做好准备
Fire!
开火
There are spirits everywhere.
这里到处都是神灵
I don't see an opening.
我看不到一个开口
Let's circle around and see if we can find a way in from the other side.
我们盘旋一周看看是不是能想办法从另一侧进入
Hold on!
坚持住
The spirits are weighing Oogi down.
这些神灵在把无忌往下拽
We're losing altitude.
我们正在下降
Get off of him, you sticky, nasty, little blob of goo!
快从它身上下去，你这个粘人又恶心的小黏球
If I go, you're coming with me.
我要是掉下去了，你也得和我一起下去
Bumi!
布米
I wish Varrick was filming this.
我希望瓦里克能把这段拍成电影
We could call it <i>Nuktuk: Sky warrior.</i>
就起名叫《纳塔克：天空战士》
Brace yourselves.
防撞姿势！
Dad.
父亲
Korra,
科拉
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
I failed you.
我辜负了你
Don't give up.
不要放弃
Harmonic convergence isn't here yet.
谐波汇聚还没有到来
We still have a chance.
我们还有机会
We tried.
我们尽力了
Congratulations, everyone.
大家伙儿，恭喜了
You've all got front-row seats for the beginning of the new world order.
你们都坐上了来观看世界新秩序开端的前排座位
You don't know what you're doing, Unalaq.
你不知道你在干什么，吴纳克
Freeing Vaatu won't make you powerful.
释放瓦图不会让你变得强大
It will only make you a traitor to everything good that's happened for the last 10,000 years.
它只会让你成为过去一万年中所有美好事物的叛徒
You think what Avatar Wan did was good?
你认为神通万做的事情是好的？
Driving almost all the spirits from this world?
从人界驱逐了几乎全部神灵？
The Avatar hasn't brought balance, only chaos.
降世神通从没有带来过和平，只有混乱
You call yourself the bridge between the two worlds,
你把自己称作两个世界的桥梁
but there shouldn't be a bridge.
但这里本就不应该有桥梁
We should live together as one.
人类和神灵应该共存
Even if Vaatu escapes,
就算瓦图逃跑了
I'll put him right back in his prison,
我也会把他关回他的牢狱
just like Wan did.
就像万做的那样
It's true that, when Wan fused with Raava, he tipped the scales in her favor.
的确当万和拉瓦合为一体时，他帮她获得了优势
But this time, I'll be here to level the playing field.
但这一次，我会来维持决斗的平等
When harmonic convergence comes, I will fuse with Vaatu.
当谐波汇聚到来时，我会与瓦图合二为一
And together, we will become the new Avatar.
我们将会一同成为新的降世神通
A dark Avatar.
暗黑逆神通
Your era is over.
你的时代结束了
Think about what you're doing.
好好想想你的所作所为
I know that you've always had a deep connection with the spirits,
我知道你一直都与神灵有着很深的联系
but you're still a man.
但你仍旧是一个人啊
You're still my brother.
你仍然是我的弟弟
You're Eska and Desna's father.
你是爱丝卡和杰斯纳的父亲
Are you willing to throw your humanity away to become a monster?
你愿意抛弃你的人性，变成一个妖魔吗？
I'll be no more of a monster than your own daughter.
我不会比你自己的女儿更像一个妖魔
The only difference is that, while she can barely recognize her own spiritual power,
唯一的区别就是，她无法认识她自己的灵力
I will be in complete alignment with mine.
我却能把自己和灵力完全结合
Vaatu and I will be as one.
瓦图和我会化为一体
No one will be able to stand against us.
没有人可以抵抗我们
Keep them locked up.
继续关着他们
After the harmonic convergence,
等谐波汇聚之后
I will come for Korra.
我会回来找科拉
Yes, father.
遵命，父亲
I failed in every way.
我完全失败了
We've lost Jinora forever.
我们永远失去吉诺拉了
There's still a chance.
我们还有一个机会
They didn't get Bumi.
他们没抓到布米
Oh, you want to play some more.
哦，你还想再找点乐子
Well, bring it on.
好啊，来吧
Oh, we're playing dirty, huh?
哦，我们玩阴的，是吧
Hmm, looks like we've got a music lover here.
看来我们这儿有个音乐爱好者
Reinforcements!
援军
All right, soldiers.
好的，士兵们
Looks like it's on us to save the day.
看来这次到我们来拯救世界了
Luckily, I've got a plan.
幸运的是，我有个计划
Eska, Desna, listen to me.
爱丝卡，杰斯纳，听我说
You've got to help us stop Unalaq.
你们一定要帮我阻止吴纳克
I know he's your father, but Vaatu has made him completely crazy.
我知道他是你们的爸爸，但是瓦图已经让他完全疯狂了
We will never turn on our father.
我们绝对不会背叛父亲
Please,
拜托
if you let me out now, I can still stop him from destroying everything.
如果你现在放我出去，我仍旧可以阻止他摧毁一切
Once he fuses with Vaatu,
一旦他和瓦图融合了
no one will be safe.
没有人能够幸免
Desna, he won't be your father anymore.
杰斯纳，他不再会是你的父亲了
You don't know what you're talking about.
你根本不明白你在说什么
Our father is the wisest man in the world.
我们父亲是这个世界上最睿智的人
If he says what he is doing is right, I believe him.
如果他说他做的是对的，我就相信他
You know, if I wanted some ball of evil lurking over my shoulder all the time,
你知道，如果要让这群邪恶的家伙一直在我周围转悠
I'd have stayed home with my mother-in-law.
我宁可陪我岳母大人呆在家里
All right, spirit army,
好了，神灵部队
your general is here. Follow me!
你们的将军在这里，跟我来
It's working.
这招奏效了
It's not working.
没奏效
Get me out of here!
放我出去
All right, guys.
好了，伙计们
Rescue time.
我来救你们啦
Bumi,
布米
how did you manage to take out this entire encampment on your own?
你是怎么一个人干掉整个营地的
I did it all with my trusty flute and...
我是与我可靠的笛子一起，还有…
oh, never mind. You wouldn't believe it anyway.
哦，算了，反正你是不会相信的
Let's get moving.
我们该动身了
You run into the portal.
你们进入通道
I'll try to hold off anyone who comes after you.
我会尽力拖住任何想要追你们的人
No, you're too hurt. You need a healer.
不行，你受伤太严重了，你需要一个水疗师
Asami, can you take Oogi and my dad back to my mom?
麻美，你能带无忌和我父亲回我母亲那里去吗
This is my fight now.
从现在起就是我的战斗了
Korra.
科拉
I love you.
我爱你
I love you too, dad.
我也爱你，父亲
Yipyip.
驾，驾
Once we're inside, you go find Jinora.
我们一旦进去后，你们去找吉诺拉
Mako and Bolin will take care of Unalaq
当我关闭通道时
while I close the portal, so Vaatu can't escape.
信和波林来对付吴纳克，这样瓦图就无法逃脱
Wait a second. Worst-case scenario.
等一下，如果发生最坏的情况
So we're fighting Unalaq, you close the portals,
我们和吴纳克作战，你关闭通道
and let's just say something happens to you.
就比方说你发生了什么情况
Are we gonna be trapped in there for eternity?
我们是不是就永远被困在那里了
If everything goes as planned, we'll all walk out together after harmonic convergence.
如果一切按照计划的进行，我们会在谐波汇聚之后一起出来
If not...
如果不行……
Let's go.
我们出发吧
Tenzin, go find Jinora.
丹增，快去找吉诺拉
Come on!
走吧
You're running out of time, Raava.
你的时间越来越少了，拉瓦
I know you feel it coming.
我知道你能感到它的到来
[Laughing maniacally]
哈×30
本作品采用知识共享CC BY-NC-SA共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可
本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流，请勿用作商业用途！
降世神通贴吧&Brony United
片源：Ult-Kimi  英文：DracoRunan  翻译：风起裘庄
校对：Ult-Kimi 调轴：水族神通